Steven Wing Full Stack Web Developer



- Steven.Thomas.Wing@gmail.com
- 236-558-3609
- a DraconianLore
- in Steven Wing

Summary

I am a Full Stack Web Developer, following my love for technology that began when I was a child. My early years were spent playing around with a Commodore 64/128, getting excited over changing the background colour of the computer screen. As I grew, so did my curiosity, I began playing with games creating mods, creating simple web pages, and even making simple games using tools such as Unity. Now, having the opportunity to change that inquisitive nature into a career, learning as much as possible along the way, I am embracing the future with an open mind, ready to tackle any challenge thrown my way.

Skills

Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, HTML/CSS/SASS, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, React, Ruby, Rails, React Native, Unity, C#, VB

Systems & Databases

Git/GitHub/Bitbucket, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Expo, Heroku

Projects

Κοῖος

July 2019

Using React Native for the front-end, Ruby-on-Rails for the back-end, and using postgres for the database. Along with Seth Marks we built this immersive game for our final project at Lighthouse Labs. We had ten days to build this app from scratch, and went from not knowing React Native at all to being able to easily navigate through our code to make changes as needed by the end of the project. I built the main framework of the back-end while Seth built the main framework for the front-end, then we just worked on feature by feature working with both the front and back as needed.

Jungle

July 2019

Using Ruby and Rails along with Sass and using postgres for the database, I took this project(from a template of A mini e-commerce application built with Rails 4.2 for purposes of teaching Rails by example.) from being riddled with bugs and terrible design to where it is now, learning ruby on rails from scratch in the week I worked on this project.

Chatty

July 2019

A compact anonymous chatroom built with nodeJS, React, WebSockets and sass. Built in 3 days after only two days of learning react. Put as many extensions as I could think of onto the application.

Conligo

June 2019

A full stack web application built with **Node, Express, Sass, and PostgreSQL with Knex**. This "Smart Todo List" categorises items the user inputs into one of four categories by using various API calls to find out what the item is. This was a group project which myself and Won Seob Shin pair programmed for the majority and worked together on the remaining parts.

Tweeter

June 2019

A single-page AJAX-based Twitter clone that uses jQuery, HTML5 and CSS3, running on a Node Express server with mongoDB.

TinyApp

June 2019

A full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs. Implemented user login and session cookies to track users and visitors.

Bar Graph Generator

May 2019

Created a bar chart drawing extension using **JavaScript**, **jQuery**, **HTML** and **CSS**. This was a stretch project completed prior to starting the Lighthouse Labs Bootcamp, using only the skills I had learnt during the month prior to working on this project. The project allows users to add a barchart to their site by simply calling the JavaScript function.

Education

Web Development Bootcamp

May 2019 - August 2019

Vancouver, BC, Canada

Lighthouse Labs

A full-time immersive web development program, covering topics such as JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, React, Node.js, Ruby, and Ruby on

Work Experience

Logistics Manager

Feb 2016 - Dec 2018

Big Mouth Foods Pty Ltd

Sydney, NSW, Australia

Coordinated a team of six drivers delivering cold foods to customers across NSW and ACT. Trained new drivers, managed inventory and coordinated with the production team. Dealt directly with customers, talking to existing and potential clients and resolving customer complaints.

Truck Manager

May 2015 - Feb 2016

Mama Linh's Food Trucks

Sydney, NSW, Australia

Managed the running of a food truck for regular street trade, and worked with the owner to run events. Direct customer service, and staff management. I learnt a lot in this position, particularly in dealing with staff and stock management.